waylandgames.co.uk 2015-12-29

# Privacy, Shipping & Returns Policy - Wayland Games

##### Privacy Policy

At Wayland Games, we're real people, just like you. So we're committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors. The following policy outlines how we treat your personal information and the security measures which are in place. For further information, please also see our [Data Protection Policy](http://www.waylandgames.co.uk/content/14-data-protection-policy)

 **What information do we collect?**

We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal data:

  * Information about your computer, your visits to and your use of this website.
  * This includes your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, the length of your visit and how many pages you viewed.
  * We also collect information regarding your transactions with us through this website, including which products you purchased to how much you spent, which coupons you redeemed and which method of devliery you chose.
  * Please note that we do not store Credit Card/Debit Card information.
  * We also collect any information that you share with us, for the purpose of registering with us, including Title, Name, Email Address, Address and Telephone Numbers.
  * This also includes information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our website services, email notifications and newsletters.
  * Plus, any other information that you choose to send to us.

##### Cookies

What is a cookie? Basically, it's a piece of tracking software which allows you to use all the features of an online retail website, like adding products to your shopping basket. Meanwhile, the online retailer is able to identify and track your activity, but only on their website. Not anywhere else.

We make use of both “session” cookies and “persistent” cookies. We use the session cookies to keep track of you while you navigate the website. Meanwhile, the persistent cookies enable our website to recognise you when you visit. So if you left something in your shopping basket last time you visited, it should still be there waiting for you when you return.

Session cookies will be deleted from your computer when you close your browser.  
Persistent cookies will remain stored on your computer until deleted, or until they reach a specified expiry date.

We use Google Analytics to collect and understand data about our website, including everything from user behaviour to our most popular pages and which product ranges generate the most revenue. Google Analytics is able to do this through the use of cookies. However, it is Google who stores this information. For more information about the data that Google stores and how we are able to access it, please read [Google's privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html).

Our advertisers and payment services providers may also send you cookies to track your online activity. But once again, this will only track your activity on their websites and our website.

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies. However, this will often have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites, including ours.

Where you submit personal information for publication on our website, we will only ever publish and use that information in accordance with the license you grant to us.

Simiarly, we will not, without your express consent, share your personal information with any third parties for the purpose of direct marketing.

##### Using Your Personal Data

There are many ways in which we can use your personal data to give you a better online shopping experience, from emailing you to let you know that your order has been despatched, to improving your browsing experience by personalising the website. But any personal data you submit to our website will only be used as outlined in this privacy policy.

We may use your personal data to:

  * Successfully manage our website.
  * Improve your browsing experience by personalising the website.
  * Allow you to keep products in your shopping basket, for purchase at the end of your sessions or when you return to the website later.
  * Take payments from you and deliver the products you've purchased, as well as send you an email notification when they have been despatched.
  * Send you general communications. Answering a help desk ticket for example.
  * Send you email notifications which you have specifically requested, like when a particular product comes back into stock or is available to order once more.
  * Send you our weekly newsletters, keeping you up to date with the latest ranges and exclusive promotions.
  * Resolve any problems which may arise relating to our website or your order with us.

##### Other Disclosures

In addition to the disclosures outlined above, which allow us to give you a great online shopping experience, we may also disclose the following information about you:

  * In connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings.
  * To establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.
  * To prevent fraud and reduce credit risk to any of our agents, suppliers or subcontractors.
  * Any futher personal information, which you expressly agree we are able to share. Your name as a winner of one of our many competitions for example.

##### Security Of Your Personal Data

We take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information.

We store all the personal information you provide on our secure (password and firewall protected) servers. And all electronic transactions you make to or receive from us are encrypted using SSL technology.

This means that we do not store any Credit Card or Debit Card information on our servers or our physical premises whatsoever.

Of course, data transmission over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet. So you are responsible for keeping your password and user details confidential. And we will never ask you for your password. This kind of sensitive information is encrypted and made inaccessible to us.

##### Policy Amendments

We may update this privacy policy from time-to-time by posting a new version on our website. So please check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes that we have made.

In the event of drastic changes to our privacy policy, we may choose to notify you by email.

##### Your Rights

You may also instruct us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes by email at any time. You will either be able to agree in advance to receive our weekly newsletters, or other form of contact in advance. And you will always be able to opt-out as well, either by clicking the Unsubscribe button at the bottom of each newsletter, or by logging in to your Wayland Games account and changing your settings.

##### Third Party Websites

Sometimes we will share links to other websites, either on our social media or from our online store for example. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of third party websites.

##### Updating Information

Please let us know if the personal information which we hold about you needs to be corrected or updated. Although you can usually do this by logging in to your Wayland Games Account and updating your personal information.

##### Contact

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our treatment of your personal data, please send us a message via our [Contact Us](http://www.teapot.waylandgames.co.uk/contact-us) page.

##### Email Notifications

We may from time to time notify all users by email of significant changes to our site which may mean that any data collected is moved or changed. For example, a server move or ecommerce platform update which would require us to migrate customers' accounts from on place to another.

##### Shipping Policy

### How do I get a shipping quote?

The best way to find out how much it costs to deliver to your location is to add a few products to your shopping basket and proceed to the checkout. From here you can enter your address and click the drop down box to see what shipping options are available to you. Each shipping option has a price and an approximate delivery time.

Some items are cheap to ship, while others are suprisingly expensive. Usually, this is due to the size and weight of your chosen products.

But if you are placing a large order, we recommend selecting the Courier options, as they offer great value (up to 30Kg in weight) and your delivery should arrive promptly while being trackable.

We will only charge what it costs us to ship an item. We will not make any profit on shipping costs. Although shipping costs are subject to change due to the postal services that we use.

Please note that the items in the catalog have a weight multiplier (20%) applied to ensure that an order will not be overweight for the shipping method chosen. However, if the final package weight is less than wat is calculated at the checkout, we will refund you the difference.

A large number of shipping options are available and will be visible at checkout. The majority of orders over £150 will be delivered by Courier for a fixed fee, which we do recommend.

 **Europe:**

Although Royal Mail see Europe as one big lump regarding costs, couriers don't. So at the moment we have Airmail and Surface Mail available with various courier options being added daily to the webstore. If our system doesn't show you a courier quote for your address, please [Contact Us](http://www.teapot.waylandgames.co.uk/contact-us) and we will get you a quote.

Please note that any item over 2Kg not sent by courier will be split into 2 or more packages.

 **Australia and New Zealand:**

Any orders over £200 will be begin to take advantage of subsidised courier shipping. The subsidy grows the more you spend. Australia and New Zealand are very expensive to ship parcels to, but we will do our best to offer the best deal possible.

Airmail and Surface Mail options are available. However, be warned that 12 weeks is the quoted time for a parcel to reach you by the Surface option. Both include insurance. These services have a 2Kg weight limit. Again as per Europe, we are able to split the order into multiple parcels. Therefore if Surface/Airmail is chosen, please be aware that any single item over 2Kg may have been opened and spread between the packages.

 **Rest Of The World:**

For the rest of the world both Surface and Airmail options are available, with couriers being added all the time. If you know of any alternative shipping carriers that can give us great rates then please let us know!

### Airmail

If an order is sent Via Airmail, it may be seperated into multiple shipments as there is a 2kg weight limit, as well as size limits on our Airmail service. Please dont be alarmed if you receive a small package that only contains part of your order. You will be receiving the rest of your order in another package, or multiple packages. Airmail generally does not allow for parcels to be tracked unless you have specifically paid for a tracked service.

### Aerosols

Aerosols cannot be sent by Air or surface shipping postage and can only be shipped by surface courier service where applicable when ordered. This is because of the air trapped within a pressurised container which has a tendency to explode due to the decreased air pressure at high altitudes.

### Shipping Times

When you place an order, the estimated dispatch time varies according to the stock status. "In Stock" items are usually dispatched within 48 hours, "Available" items can take between 3 and 9 working days to arrive from the supplier and ship out. This is an average and some special items may take longer. We aim to get the orders packaged and out of the door as soon as possible. But at busy times and after public holidays, there can be a small backlog. Also bear in mind the delivery method selected does not impact the processing-packing-dispatch process. It is simply how quickly your order will be delivered from our warehouse.

##### Returns Policy

If you are not 100% satisfied with your purchase from Wayland Games, you can return your items for a full refund within 7 days of the original delivery date.

Returns must be unopened, in the state you received them, and in the original packaging.

Please note that you will be responsible for the return shipping amount and that we cannot accept returned merchandise without a Return Material Authorisation (RMA).

If the product is defective or the return is a result of our error, please notify us within 14 days of receipt of the item and we will pay the return shipping costs to a maximum of £8.50.

Instructions for returns will be supplied in response to an email. So please [Contact Us](http://www.teapot.waylandgames.co.uk/contact-us) and wait for a reply before you return anything.

It may take 4-5 business days for your return to reach Wayland Games. Although it could take up to 20 or more if you are shipping from overseas. But once it is received and inspected (usually within 72 hours of receipt) your refund will be processed and automatically applied to your credit card or original method of payment within 7 days.

Please note that depending on your credit card company, it may take an additional 2-10 business days after your credit is applied for it to post to your account.

For questions regarding our returns policy please [Contact Us](http://www.teapot.waylandgames.co.uk/contact-us).

##### Free Shipping Terms and Conditions

We often run Free Shipping promotions, which you can usually qualify for by spending a certain amount with us or entering a special coupon code at the checkout. However, each Free Shipping promotion has its own terms and conditions. Meanwhile, certain products, such as heavy, bulky items and aerosols are not included in these promotions.

Typically our Free Shipping promotional terms and conditions include:

  * The promotion must be claimed by including the correct voucher code within a single order of goods that is priced at £30 or more.
  * The promotion will comprise free standard shipping on qualifying orders.
  * Bulky items, aerosols and paint are excluded. What constitutes a bulky item shall be at Wayland Games Limited's discretion.
  * Regretfully we are unable to offer free shipping under this promotion to destination addresses in Brazil and the Russian Federation. Any orders placed using this voucher destined for Brazil or the Russian Federation shall be cancelled and refunded.
  * Courier shipping upgrades remain at standard price.
  * There is no cash alternative.

Please note that during a free shipping promotion, due to the large influx of orders, order processing times may be slightly impacted.
